unitravel.com 2018-03-11

# Unitravel.com - Privacy

This website belongs and is managed by UniTravel Srl, hereinafter UniTravel, an Italian Company with registered office in Via Brunacci 9/b, Venice Italy, Vat Code 03458490277. It makes part of the circuit of portals that head to the website www.unitravel.com, hereinafter called UniTravel Network or simply the Network. 

UniTravel is aware of the importance of security and discretion of personal data and carefully handles collected data, not only to respect regulations in force, but to safeguard the confidence placed in UniTravel by the Users. 

All the pages where UniTravel collect and process personal data are protected and encrypted by SSL ("Secure Socket Layer") and personal data and credit card data is encrypted. Our SSL certificate has been issued by Thawte, a leading company in online security protocol (http://www.thawte.com). 

UniTravel furthermore comply to the **PCI DSS standard** that defines the set of rules set by the PCI Council, the organization founded by American Express, Discover Financial Services, JCB International, MasterCard Worldwide and Visa Inc.. (https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org) responsible for defining security standards for account data protection and payments. 

UniTravel has developed its own Security Policy Document containing specifications adopted by UniTravel for the protection of personal data. This document was notified to the Italian Privacy Autority (CUN Italian Code: 0000-0285-6310-1466). 

The present document defines the policy adopted by UniTravel with regards to personal data protection and defines, together with the General Terms and Conditions (Terms & Conditions) the terms named by UniTravel for the use of services provided through the network. 

The navigation, the use of the reservation system and all other services provided by UniTravel, the sending of information trough the Network websites or the creation of an account means that the present conditions are well-known and accepted by the User. 

### Security and Privacy

The present statement is aimed at guaranteeing the security and privacy of personal data left by the Users. Personal data means information that is able to identify a specific person, for example name, last name, address, telephone number and e-mail address.  
Given the importance of this subject to UniTravel, the following conditions describe the manner in which personal information will be treated and used. It refers to information that is found in art.  
13 del d.lgs. n. 196/2003 - A code that protects personal information and applies to services distributed by UniTravel and its network. This privacy statement is only for the websites that are run by and belong to UniTravel and not for other Websites that the user may link to. 

### The "holder" of data processing

UniTravel S.r.l is the holder of the data, with its Head Office situated in Venice, Italy, Via Brunacci 9/b, P IVA 03458490277, registered in Venice, Italy N REA VE-310017. 

### Place of Data Processing

The treatment of the data which is connected to the service will be processed in the offices of UniTravel S.r.l, Via Brunacci 9/b, 30175 Venice, Italy, where only authorized people are assigned to processing such data, using DPS (Security Data Program) approved by the company.  
Once the reservation has been supplied through third party, the data collected in relation to the booking is presented to the supplier with whom the booking has been made (such as the reserved hotel) and will therefore be processed by the supplier in respect to the terms and condition laid down by the respective privacy policy. 

### Nature of requested Data 

The data that UniTravel receives from the User is provided voluntarily and can have an obligatory or optional nature. For example to make a reservation, the request of data such as the reservation name, email address and the credit card information are mandatory fields that guarantees the booking, meaning that without this information the reservation cannot be made, while, at the same time fields which are optional, such as the address or fax of the person making the reservation, will not impede the reservation. 

### Processing of data

The processing of data will be carried out with the aid of electronic instruments as well as paper, in order to guarantee security and confidentiality, with means capable of preventing the risk of loss or destruction, unauthorized access or treatment not allowed, or damage to the integrity or confidentiality of data. 

### The User’s rights

The Users of which UniTravel collect data have the right to know the contents of the data collected in any form and are able to know where the information came from, to verify its accuracy, supplement, or update or correct data (art 7. of the Legislative Decree n.196/2003).  
In conformity with the same article, the Users have the right to ask for cancellation, transformation of the data into an anonymous form in case of right withhold data which is seen to be against the law, in addition to oppose the data being processed for legal reasons.  
In particular, users are entitled to exercise all rights under Art. 7 of the Privacy Code (Right of access to personal data and other rights) which for convenience we list below:  
1\. User has the right to obtain confirmation of the existence or not of personal data concerning him, even if not yet recorded, and their communication in an intelligible form;  
2\. The user has the right to obtain the indication:  
a) of the origin of personal data;  
b) of the purposes and methods of treatment;  
c) of the logic applied in case of treatment with the aid of electronic instruments;  
d) of the identity of the owner, manager and the representative appointed under article 5, paragraph 2  
e) of the subjects or categories of subjects to whom the personal data may be communicated or who can learn about them as appointed representative in the State, responsibles or designated to.  
3\. The user has the right to obtain:  
a) the updating, rectification or, when interested, integration of data;  
b) the cancellation, transformation into anonymous form or blocking of data processed unlawfully, including data which need not be kept for the purposes for which the data were collected or subsequently processed;   
c) the certification that the operations in letters a) and b) have been notified, as also related to their contents, to those to whom the data were communicated or disseminated, unless this requirement is impossible or involves the use of means manifestly disproportionate to the protected right.  
4\. The user has the right to take position against, in whole or in part:  
a) the processing of personal data, pertinent to the collection purposes, for legitimate reasons;  
b) the processing of personal data concerning him with the purpose of sending advertising materials or direct selling or for carrying out market research or commercial communication.

Such requests must be sent to UniTravel S.r.l, Via Brunacci 9/b, 30175 Venice Italy, to fax number +39 041 8620433 or via mail to the above mentioned address. 

#### Type of data and purpose of processing 

**Following shows how and in which occasions the data will be collected. In addition specific information is available to UniTravel through the pages where the services, like the reservation of a property or form completion etc. can be seen. The main sources are:**

### Completion of the hotel reservation

The data is essential when carrying out the reservation procedure therefore without the appropriate data, the service requested could be impossible to obtain.  
During the reservation process, personal data is collected and UniTravel gives information about data collection during this process. 

### Use of credit card information

UniTravel collects all relative credit card information, the credit card number and type, the name of the credit card holder and the expiry date and sends them directly to the booked property, ensuring that should the User not arrive at the property appropriate charges will apply.  
In specific cases, well highlighted on the website and related to explicit reservations and/or rate conditions, UniTravel can use the credit card data provided by the User to charge the whole amount of the service booked, on its own behalf or on behalf of third parties.  
UniTravel uses Thawte, a world leader certificate for the identification service on the internet. SSL secure navigation protocol is used when entering personal data for the reservation process (including credit card data).  
Furthermore UniTravel comply to the **PCI DSS standard** that defines the set of rules set by the PCI Council, the organization founded by American Express, Discover Financial Services, JCB International, MasterCard Worldwide and Visa Inc.. (https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org) responsible for defining security standards for account data protection and payments. 

### Communication regarding the reservation

UniTravel will send all communication relating to the reservation, including changes and cancellations to the email address provided when at the time data was collected. UniTravel will only telephone in case of emergency relating to the reservation. 

### Site feedback

UniTravel offers the User the possibility to express opinions about the site, without feeling obligated to do so. The feedback relating to his stay, can be in any form chosen by the User, either from the data already given to UniTravel or by using a nickname or anonymously communicating the information. . 

### User registration 

UniTravel gives the User the possibility to voluntarily create an account in order to become a registered User. In such case he will be asked to give some information of which some mandatory and some optional, (e.g. name, phone number, fax number, e-mail address, a username and a password).   
Such information are collected in the registration form to identify the User, to complete hotel and tourist service reservations in general, to contact the User for customer care, to make a research in order to improve products and services offered on the site.   
Furthermore the e-mail address is requested to send the registration number and confirmation e-mail of each reservation made on-line.   
In case the User provides a fax number, he can ask to receive this information via fax. In order to monitor the effectiveness of our communication via electronic mail, we can include a system to verify the visualization of the message and to monitor the actions of the User.  
The information on the visits are collected to offer products or services that cold be of interest for the User. The User can be sent recurring updates on special offers, services or new products.   
If the User don’t wish to receive such news via e-mail or fax, he can ask to unsubscribe trough an automated procedure. The registration will enable the User to make bookings without entering the same data each time.   
In case the User decides to save his preferences about travelling, etc., he can receive personalized information based on what he indicated and therefore closer to his needs. 

### Newsletters

UniTravel creates its own newsletter to send material for promotional and commercial purposes about tourist products and services. At the moment of subscription to the newsletter service, the User is asked to provide data that enable UniTravel to contact him, such as his name and e-mail address. To respect the privacy of our Users, UniTravel sends the newsletter only to those who made a specific request on his own. At any moment the User can ask to unsubscribe.  
**\- Sending emails to addresses found on the website** The optional, explicit and voluntary sending of electronic mail to the addresses indicated on this website entails the subsequent acquisition of the sender, necessary to respond to requests, and of any other personal data included in the message. 

### Procedure of withdrawal of consent to promotional communication

The Users of the network can deny at any moment the permission to use personal information for promotional purposes. Users that don’t want to receive newsletters and promotional offers can use opt-out to suspend the subscription to the service, replying to e-mails and using the term "unsubscribe" in the object or selecting links for the unsubscription procedure. Requests may also be sent to UniTravel Srl, Via Brunacci 9 / b, 30175 Venice, Italy, to the fax number +39 041 8620433 or by mail at the above address. 

### Links to other sites

The UniTravel network sites may contain links to third party sites that not share with UniTravel any information. UniTravel is not responsible for the action, security and privacy of such websites at all. Upon leaving the UniTravel network the User must exercise extreme caution when asked for any personal data, and should check, in the third party sites, the data protection policy in a document like this one. 

### Answers to questions and suggestions

UniTravel will contact either by email or telephone the user, should any questions need answering or suggestions or assistance be requested. In these cases, the supplied data can be dealt according to the present informative report. 

### Ability to check the use of personal data and self access

UniTravel believes that both users and visitors should have control of the data collected and how the data should be used. Requests can be made by contacting UniTravel S.r.l, Via Brunacci 9/b, 30175 Venice, Italy on +39 041 8620433 or by the email address written below. 

### UniTravel communication

Users will receive communication when:  
**\- A reservation is made, changed or a cancelled;** ;  
**\- Every time a reservation has been made through UniTravel, or a change or a cancellation of a confirmed reservation, UniTravel will send an email notifying of such operation.** ;  
**\- A registration to the Network is made;** ;   
**\- A registration to the newsletter service is made;** ;   
**\- Request of client support or questions/suggestions/form compilation;**  
**\- When help is needed regarding the booking, or about how the site works, UniTravel will reply by email or telephone;**  
**\- Opinions are being asked about their stay or website use;** ;  
**\- - After checking out of the property booked through UniTravel, the User will receive an email containing links to a form asking for their opinions about the place where they had their stay.** ;  

### Declaration of Commitment

UniTravel agree not to send unsolicited commercial communications without first obtaining the consent of the User. 

### Sharing of collected data to third parties

UniTravel communicate the data collected exclusively to its partner providers of services required by Users or partners who perform certain functions on behalf of UniTravel or as permitted by law. UniTravel not sell, rent or leases it to any personal data collected.  
To provide the service of booking UniTravel collects data of Users and with their consent we may share the information collected with the following categories of persons:  
\- The supplier of the service booked (hotels and accommodation facilities, other service providers ). The service provider may contact you on the basis of data collected by UniTravel to get more information, facilitate the booking, or to respond to specific requests and more generally for reasons related to the reservation;  
\- Third Party Operators, providing a service or carry out activities on behalf of/or with UniTravel with wich UniTravel has collaboration agreements. UniTravel may in some cases allow other operators to collect information on its behalf, eg. to handle some functionality of their websites, or to make online advertising services responsive to the interests of users. These third-party operators have access to and may collect information only as necessary to carry out their activities and he is not allowed to share or use the information for any other reason. UniTravel require to third party operators to follow the same security rules applied by UniTravel. In such cases, strictly necessary to provide the service, UniTravel takes specific agreements in order for them to have in place privacy policies equivalent to those of UniTravel. UniTravel is committed to making every effort to protect personal information collected in accordance with the highest standards of personal data protection;  
\- Business partners with whom UniTravel may jointly offer products or services, or whose products or services may be offered on the sites of the network UniTravel . In such cases UniTravel could share information of users and their personal data with these partners;  
\- Linked Web Sites . If you arrive at one of the network sites UniTravel coming from another site ( for example , clicking on a link on another website, search engine or similar) UniTravel may be required to share data with that site. We suggest users to search and read the privacy policies for each website that links to one of the network sites UniTravel or is lynched by UniTravel. 

### UniTravel Obligations

UniTravel may be required to communicate the data collected if the authority requests to do so and if this is due pursuant to the law or by way of self-defense against unlawful conduct of Users or to protect and defend the rights, property , or safety of UniTravel of their sites or to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of users, suppliers or other parties with whom UniTravel have collaborative relationships; 

### Cookies and other technologies

Cookies are data sets stored in the User's PC (or mobile device), sometimes, but not always, linked to your personal information, which serve to provide information to the web sites visited to enhance the experience of use of the sites. 

### Cookies and Navigation of the Network websites

No personal data is collected during simple navigation. In such occasion cookies are not used for transmitting personal information. The use of cookies is limited to the transmission of the session (made by the random numbers of the server) in order to ensure the safe and efficient working of the site. The cookies used in the session are to avoid repetition of other potential harmful technical information while navigating the site and does not consent the acquisition of personal data. The information systems and the software procedures available, acquire in the normal course of operation, some data which is implicit in the use of communication protocols of the Internet. This information are not collected to be associated to identified Users, but for their nature could permit to identify Users through data elaboration ad associations with third-party data.  
This category of data includes IP addresses or the domain names of the computer used by the Users connected to the site, the URI address (Uniform Resource Identifier) of the requested resource, the time requested, the method used to request the server, the file dimension obtained upon response, the numeric code indicating the state of the data from the server (first-rate completion, errors etc) and other relative parameters of the operating system and the information systems used by the User.  
The data collected are used only to retrieve anonymous information for statistical purposes and to ensure that the website is working correctly. The data can be used to ascertain responsibility should there be hypothetical crimes that could be damaging to the site.  
For example , UniTravel use cookies on its sites to store a user's search while continuing to navigate. Other cookies help UnItarvel to understand the preferences of the User, to introduce features that improve the browsing experience of the site or its usability, or to evaluate, with our partners, the effectiveness of advertisements on our site and to check how users use the site. In other cases UniTravel use cookies in conjunction with our suppliers to develop more advanced features (so-called third party cookies) that allow you to access the functionality of their sites by accessing our sites, and vice versa, such as when we use the maps or advertising services developed by third parties. In such cases, the cookies do not provide personal data but only recognize generic features on the PC (or mobile device) User.  
Third-party cookies also includes those generated by social networking sites, which are offered on certain pages of the network UniTravel, with the aim of promoting ("share", "like") services. They are clearly recognizable logos and/or names of their networks (such as Facebook and Google+). No personal data is transmitted via these cookies, the purpose of which, is only to associate the current Url in UniTravel with the user's social network websites, allowing users to perform the requested operation (such as "like" on Facebook website).  
The Network uses both session cookies (temporary) that persistent cookies. The session cookies vanish permanently once the browser is closed. Persistent cookies are small text files that remain on the hard disk of the User for a given period of time.  
UniTravel uses cookies for various purposes.  
For example, cookies can be used to automatically recognize the user login again without these log-in. Cookies can also be used to track the navigation paths of the User to better understand the way in which a user uses a site.  
Users can always decide to accept or not coockies, properly configuring the browser options. However, choosing the latter option, the use of the sites could be limited to some parts and to a lower range of features. 

#### Here's how the main occasions when UniTravel uses cookies:

### Advanced use of navigation of the Network websites

UniTravel uses cookies with a lifespan of 30 days. The cookies created by this website do not contain any personally identifiable data.  
The cookies are used only to optimize the experience when using the website.  
When the user provides personal data and agrees the handling of such data, the are memorized ad associated to the code of the cookie, so that the User is automatically recognized when navigating the website.  
When the cookie expires or if the User logs-out, such association is eliminated.  
At any moment it is possible to disable cookies from your web browser in order not to receive the cookies, or set the browser asking whether or not to accept the cookies. UniTravel however informs you, by disabling or not accepting the cookies can limit the use to the services available and advanced functions of the reservation system. 

### Tags

Within marketing operations driven by UniTravel or consociates, we can use technological systems to register such information on the reservations made by the Users through our website. The information collected are anonymous and encloses the entire amount of the operation and the reservation code generated by the system. Such data are used to verify the effectiveness of our market researches and can be transmitted to our consociates for similar purposes. The collection and elaboration of data can be made by external suppliers. 

### Registry Logs

Like the majority of servers, UniTravel uses log files. They include IP addresses, server type, ISP, origin and exit pages, time of visit and number of clicks. This file are use to analyse trends, manage the web site, track navigation, find problems and collect general demographic information on the use of aggregate IP. Addresses, etc. are not connected to identifying information of personal matter. 

### Changes to the present document

The present document regarding privacy has been inserted in the site on October 15, 2013. UniTravel reserves the right to modify this document at any time and for any reason. For substantial changes to the present document or about the way that UniTravel uses personal data, UniTravel will inform all users in the appropriate manner and with plenty of notice, before proceeding.  
Independently to further updates, UniTravel will respect all procedures relating to the present document on privacy published at the time when the data was supplied. 

### Applicable Law

This information is subject to regulations in Italy, a country where UniTravel Srl has its registered office, its operational offices and where it operates and where the law will be applied and regulated in accordance with the laws of the Italian Republic , without any conflict.  
The User accepts the exclusive jurisdiction of the Judicial Italian law for the resolution of any dispute related to this policy (including, but not limited to, those relating to its validity, application, interpretation, execution).  
In the event of a dispute arising in any way from this policy it will be of exclusive jurisdiction of the Judicial Authority of the Courts of Venice.  
This agreement is drawn up in the Italian language. Should it be translated into any other language, this is done solely for the greater convenience of the other party. In the event of any disputes or conflicts regarding its interpretation, the version drawn up in the Italian language shall prevail to all legal effects.
